{
  "meta": {
    "learningGoals": "<par>In this skill you learn to <term>solve a linear equation with multiple variables and with fractions</term>. If you have an equation like <inline-math/> then you will be able to determine the solution for <inline-math/> as <inline-math/>. This includes <skill-link>simplifying the fraction with a fraction sum into a single fraction</skill-link>, <skill-link>multiplying equation terms by denominators</skill-link> and eventually <skill-link>solving the resulting linear equation</skill-link>.</par>"
  },
  "theory": {
    "intro": "<par>Consider an equation like <inline-math/> where the target variable <inline-math/> is in the denominator of some fraction. Sometimes such an equation is a <term>linear equation in disguise</term>. Here we learn how to check that, and how to subsequently solve such equations.</par>",
    "solving": "<head>Solving the linear equation</head><par>We can now <skill-link>solve the linear equation</skill-link> in the standard way. Expanding brackets gives <block-math/> Bringing all terms with <inline-math/> to the left and all other terms to the right, we wind up with <block-math/> Pulling <inline-math/> out of brackets then reduces this to <block-math/> The final solution follows by dividing by the term between brackets, giving <block-math/> This is the solution of the equation.</par>",
    "cleaning": "<head>Cleaning up the equation</head><par>The first thing that we always do is clean up the equation. If there are any fractions inside of fractions, we first want to solve that, <skill-link>reducing it to a single fraction</skill-link>. For the example, we can multiply the numerator and denominator of the fraction on the left by <inline-math/> to get <block-math/> After this, we note that the target variable <inline-math/> is still in the denominator. We can solve this by <skill-link>multiplying all terms</skill-link> by <inline-math/>. Optionally, we can also multiply all terms by <inline-math/> to get rid of the fraction on the right. This results in <block-math/> We have ensured that there are no fractions anymore with <inline-math/> in the denominator, so we have sufficiently cleaned up the equation. Now we see that the equation is in fact linear in <inline-math/>. That is, there are no powers of <inline-math/> or similar. Only multiplications by constants and non-target variables (which can also be seen as constants).</par>",
    "checking": "<head>Checking the solution</head><par>It is still wise to check the solution. To do so, we insert the solution into the original equation. Doing so gets us <block-math/> Simplifying the innermost fraction turns this into <block-math/> Multiplying both sides of the outer fraction by <inline-math/> further reduces this to <block-math/> Finally getting rid of the brackets, canceling the <inline-math/> term and subsequently canceling the factor <inline-math/> in the fraction will reduce this to <block-math/> This equation obviously holds, which means that the solution we found is correct.</par>",
    "steps": "<head>The steps</head><par>To solve a linear equation in disguise, like <inline-math/>, for a target variable <inline-math/>, take the following steps.</par><list><item><a>If there are any fractions within fractions, <skill-link>reduce these to single fractions</skill-link>. This turns the example into <inline-math/>.</a></item><item><b>If the target variable is in any denominator, <skill-link>multiply all terms by this denominator</skill-link> to fix this. Optionally, you can get rid of all fractions; also those without the target variable in the denominator. For the example, we rewrite the equation to <inline-math/>.</b></item><item><c>If the equation indeed is linear, then <skill-link>solve the linear equation</skill-link> in the standard way. In the example, if we expand brackets, move terms around, pull <inline-math/> out of brackets and divide by this factor, we end up with <inline-math/>.</c></item></list>"
  },
  "practice": {
    "multipleBasicFractions": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve it for <inline-math/>. Simplify your result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Rewrite the equation such that it does not have any fractions anymore.",
        "solution": "We multiply all terms with both <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>. For the first term, <inline-math/> disappears from the denominator, and the remaining factor is multiplied by <inline-math/>. For the other two terms, it is <inline-math/> that disappears from the denominator, and the remaining factors are multiplied by <inline-math/>. The result is <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting simplified equation for <inline-math/>. Simplify your result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "The equation is linear, so we take the default plan of approach. First we expand all brackets to get <block-math/> We then move all terms with <inline-math/> to one side and all terms without <inline-math/> to the other side. That is, <inline-math/> moves to the left and <inline-math/> goes to the right. This gives <block-math/> Next, we pull <inline-math/> out of brackets. This turns the above into <block-math/> Finally we divide both sides of the equation by <inline-math/> to solve for <inline-math/>. The result is <block-math/>"
      }
    },
    "extraFractionInNumerator": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve it for <inline-math/>. Simplify your result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Reduce the fraction of fractions into a single fraction. (Leave the rest of the equation unchanged.)",
        "solution": "The short-cut towards simplifying the fraction of fractions is multiplying the numerator and the denominator by <inline-math/> and subsequently dividing them by <inline-math/>. <check><on-true>Through this,</on-true><on-false>Through this, and through the cancellation of minus signs,</on-false></check> the fraction reduces to <block-math/> By inserting this into the equation, we can write it as <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Rewrite the equation such that it does not have any fractions anymore.",
        "solution": "We multiply both sides of the equation by <inline-math/> After canceling out factors, we remain with <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting simplified equation for <inline-math/>. Simplify your result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "The equation is linear, so we take the default plan of approach. We move all terms with <inline-math/> to one side and all terms without <inline-math/> to the other side. In this case it's easier to bring <inline-math/> to the right, such that <block-math/> Next, we pull <inline-math/> out of brackets. This turns the above into <block-math/> Finally we divide both sides of the equation by <inline-math/> to solve for <inline-math/>. The result is <block-math/>"
      }
    },
    "extraFractionInDenominator": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve it for <inline-math/>. Simplify your result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Reduce the fraction of fractions into a single fraction. (Leave the rest of the equation unchanged.)",
        "solution": "The short-cut towards simplifying the fraction of fractions is multiplying the numerator and the denominator by both <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>. This turns the fraction into <block-math/> By inserting this into the equation, we can write it as <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Rewrite the equation such that it does not have any fractions anymore.",
        "solution": "We multiply both sides of the equation by both <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>. After canceling out factors, we remain with <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting simplified equation for <inline-math/>. Simplify your result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "The equation is linear, so we take the default plan of approach. First we expand all brackets to get <block-math/> We then move all terms with <inline-math/> to one side and all terms without <inline-math/> to the other side. That is, <inline-math/> moves to the left, such that <block-math/> Next, we pull <inline-math/> out of brackets. This turns the above into <block-math/> Finally we divide both sides of the equation by <inline-math/> to solve for <inline-math/>. The result is <block-math/>"
      }
    },
    "crossExercise": {
      "rightSideChanged": "<a>Leave the right side of the equation unchanged!</a>"
    }
  }
}